<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The manner of the cruell outragious murther of William Storre Mast. of Art, minister, and preacher at Market Raisin in the county of Lincolne committed by Francis Cartwright one of his parishioners, the 30. day of August anno. 1602.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1603</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 20 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 6 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A13002</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 23295</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S111286</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99846659</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99846659</idno>
            <idno type="VID">11643</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A13002)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 11643)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1189:1)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The manner of the cruell outragious murther of William Storre Mast. of Art, minister, and preacher at Market Raisin in the county of Lincolne committed by Francis Cartwright one of his parishioners, the 30. day of August anno. 1602.</title>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[12] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by Ioseph Barnes,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>At Oxford :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1603.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signatures: A⁴ B² .</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of a photostat of the original in the Henry E. Huntington Library and Art Gallery.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Storr, William, 1563 or 4-1602.</term>
               <term>Cartwright, Francis.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-07</date>
            <label>Lauren Proux</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:11643:1"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:11643:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <p>THE MANNER OF THE CRVELL OVT<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>RAGIOVS MVRTHER OF WILLIAM STORRE <hi>Maſt. of Art,</hi> Mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>niſter, and Preacher at Market Raiſin in the County of Lincolne:</p>
            <p>COMMITTED <hi>By Francis Cartwright one of his pariſhioners, the</hi> 30. <hi>day of August Anno.</hi> 1602.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>printer's or publisher's device</figDesc>
               <head>AC: OX</head>
            </figure>
            <p>
               <hi>AT OXFORD,</hi> Printed by Ioſeph Barnes. 1603.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="account">
            <pb facs="tcp:11643:2"/>
            <p>
               <pb facs="tcp:11643:2"/>
               <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Bout Lammas laſt <hi>viz. Ann.</hi> 1602. there happened ſome controverſie betweene the Lords and the reſt of the Inhabita<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ts of <hi>Market Raiſin</hi> in the county of <hi>Lin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>colne,</hi> concerning their co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>mons &amp; liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty in the Towne-Fields, and the matter beeing moved by one of them in the Church immediatly after evening prai<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>er, on a Sabboth day, divers hot intem<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perate ſpeaches paſſed among them. Wherevpon their Mini<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſter, whoſe name was <hi>M. Storre,</hi> much diſliking ſo indiſcreete a courſe, willed them to haue reſpect both to the time, and place where they were. And further adviſed; ſeeing the cauſe in hand concerned a multitude, amongſt whom ſome of the leaſt go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, would alwaies bee the readieſt to ſpeake: that they would therefore make choice of two or three of the fitteſt, and moſt ſubſtantiall men to anſwere, and vndertake for all the reſt. This motion ſeemed to pleaſe them well, and therevpon they intreated him, that he would, as a man indifferent, ſpeake firſt what he thought concerning the cauſe. But he not willing to intermeddle in that matter, twiſe, or thriſe denied their requeſt. And the rather for that there was preſent one <hi>Fra<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>cis Cartwright,</hi> a young man of an vnbridled humor: the only ſonne, &amp; heire to one of the ſame Lords of the Towne, betwixt whom, &amp; him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe there was growne no ſmall vnkindneſſe. Yet in the ende being preſſed thervnto by their importunity, with the conſent of both the parties, he delivered his opinion, vſing therein ſuch diſcretion, and reaſons to confirme the ſame, that they coulde not directly except againſt him. Notwithſtanding ſeeing him incline more to the right of the free-holders, and the reſt of the commons, than to favour their intended purpoſe, they ſeemed to diſlike his ſpeeches and to cavill at the ſame.</p>
            <p>Young <hi>Cartwright</hi> ſtanding by, not able any longer to con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taine himſelfe, tooke occaſio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> herevpon to break forth abrupt<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly into theſe words. <hi>The Prieſt deſerveth a good fee, he speaketh ſo like a Lawyer, M. Storre</hi> having often aforetime had experience of his hot ſtomacke, &amp; haſtineſſe aſwell towards others as him<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſelfe, thought it beſt to reply little againſt him for that preſent. But the other reſpecting neither the time, nor place, nor yet the
<pb facs="tcp:11643:3"/>
dutifull regard he ſhould haue had to his fathers preſence, vtte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red manie moe ſuch baſe &amp; odious tearmes, that for modeſtie ſake, I forbeare to rehearſe the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>. The next morning as M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Storre, &amp; ſome others of his neighbours were talking with the elder Cartwright about theſe his ſonnes abuſes, hee came vnto them, where they were, interrupting their conference, &amp; fell into the like outragious railing as he vſed the night afore. The Miniſter ſeeing this ſecond incurſion more violent then the former, re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>plied to ſome of his words, retorting the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> backe againe, as more properly to be applied to himſelfe.</p>
            <p>This reply he tooke in ſuch high diſgrace, that had not his fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther hindred it, he had there preſently with his dagger effected ſome part of that miſchiefe, which afterward he putt in practiſe. But being not ſuffered to do what he would, he departed from the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> into the ope<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> market place, &amp; there proclaimed, <hi>That Storre was a ſcurvy, lowſie, paltrie prieſt: that whoſoever ſaid he was his friend, or spake in his cauſe, was a rogue, &amp; a raſcall: that he would (but for the law) cut his throat, tear out his hart, &amp; ha<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>g his quarters on the maypole.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Theſe ſpeeches, &amp; many moe of the ſame quality being day<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly giuen out, occaſioned M<hi rend="sup">r</hi> Storre to thinke it now high time to provide for his owne ſafetie, &amp; therfore he went to ſome Iu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtices neere adioyning: acquainted the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> with theſe proceedings, &amp; deſired the good behaviour againſt the ſaid Cartwright. But they doubting whether they might gra<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t the ſame in this caſe, or not, offered him for his preſent ſafegard the peace, and the other at the next quarter ſeſſions, if occaſion ſo required.</p>
            <p>He not reſolved what were beſt to bee done, whether to ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cept of this offer, or to complaine himſelfe before the high com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſioners, came home, &amp; the next Sabaoth tooke his text out of <hi>Iſaah Chap.</hi> 1. <hi>verſ.</hi> 9. in theſe words. <hi>Except the Lord of Hoſtes had reſerved vnto vs, even a ſmall remnant, we had bin as Sodom, and like vnto Gomorah.</hi> The which words by the generall report, even of his enemies that hard him, he handled verie learnedly, and delivered out of the ſame many points of neceſſary doctrine. yong <hi>Cartwright</hi> ſeemed to note it diligently with his pen, but as the ſtomake filled with rawe humors corrupteth all good nou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>riſhme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t that co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>meth therin, ſo this mans mind fraught with ran<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cour, &amp; malice, wreſted al things he heard into the worſe ſenſe, as purpoſely ſpoken againſt him, and after that, more, and more
<pb facs="tcp:11643:3"/>
thirſted for revenge.</p>
            <p>About a weeke after, hee eſpied Mr. Storre walking about eight of the clock in the morning alone by the ſouth ſide of the towne in his cloake, went to a cutlers ſhoppe, tooke out of the ſame a ſhort ſword, which he had formerly provided, and made very ſharp, &amp; preſently overtooke him. The other hearing one at his heeles looked backe, &amp; ſawe him drawing his ſword as he came: noting alſo by the palenes of his viſage, how mightely he was incenſed to miſchiefe, &amp; ſeeing no means either to eſcape, or to defend himſelfe, was greatly agaſt, &amp; purpoſed to vſe ſome ſpeeches (if it were poſſible) ſomewhat to aſſwage his paſſions.</p>
            <p>But he being double armed both with force, &amp; fury, would a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bide no parly, but preſently at the firſt blow cutt his lefte legge almoſt of, &amp; then making at his head, the other caſting vp his armes to defend it (for other weapon had he none) he gaue him two mortal wou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ds on the forepart therof thorow the brain-pan: cut of three of his fingers: &amp; gaue him other two grievous wou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ds on the outſide of either arme, betweene the elbow, &amp; the hand, the one to the middeſt of the arme, &amp; the other more the<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> halfe in ſunder, deviding the maine bone aboue two ynches one part fro<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> another. Thus maſſacred he fell backward into a puddle of water, and ſtriving to recover himſelfe, the ſplinter bone of his legge halfe cut thorow afore, knapt in two, &amp; his heele doubled back to the calfe of his legge. <hi>Cartright</hi> not yet ſatisfied with the bloud, which he had already gotten, continued his rage, ſtill more feircely vpo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> him, &amp; gaue him another gaſh on the outſide of the right thigh to the very bone. And again on the left knee, his legge being bended, as he lay, he cut him the faſhion, &amp; co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>
               <g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſſe of an horſe ſhoe battring in pieces the whirlbone, &amp; the ne<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther part of the thighe bone, that it was moſt grievous eve<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> to be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>hold. Some ſmaler wou<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ds he had, &amp; ſundry other blowes which came not to his skin, as appeared by the ma<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>gling of his apparel.</p>
            <p>A maide co<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ming that way by occaſion of buſines cried out, whervpon he fled, and many of the neighbors came preſently to the place, and behoulding this vvoefull ſpectacle, their Miniſter thus wallowed in the mire, and his bloude ſo ex<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>treamely, guſhing out, ranne ſome of them into the tovvne vvith ſuch a confuſed noyſe, and outcrie of murther, that others hearing it, ſuppoſed on the ſudden there had beene
<pb facs="tcp:11643:4"/>
fire, and went with all ſpeede to towle the bells. Thus was all ſuddenly in an vproare, yet fewe, or none could tell what the matter was. The reſt of more diſcretion tooke vp the wounded man, carried him to the next houſe, where one of the conſtables dwelt, and made very good, and ſpeedy meanes to bind vp his wounds, and to ſtanch his bloud.</p>
            <p>Againſt the next day was provided a bone-ſetter, and three or foure of the beſt ſurgeons thereabout, who when they came to dreſſe him, were of opinion, that, if hee died not at the ope<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ning of his wounds, and forcing togither of his bones, he would at the leaſt be verie ſubiect to often ſounding. Yet hee beyond all their expectation indured all extremities, which neceſſitie in that caſe impoſed on him to abide, for three houres ſpace at the leaſt, and never fainted, or changed colour. The which thinge induced them to alter their minde, and to hope (as it were) paſt all hope, that he would eſcape it. But the deadly blowes had ſo periſhed his braines, and let out ſo great a quantitie of his bloud in other partes of his body, that it was not poſſible he ſhould re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cover. So that after he had languiſhed in verie great paine from monday morning till the nexte Sunday after midnight, which was at the change of the moone, he ended his life.</p>
            <p>The time that he thus continued, he ſpent much to the pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fitte of himſelfe, and to no leſſe comfort of thoſe that came to viſite him. For beſides many divine meditations he daily vtte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red, &amp; thanks to God for his ſo mercifull a viſitation, in giving him both ſuch time, and memory to prepare himſelfe, hee alſo hartely forgaue, &amp; continuallie praied for his greateſt, &amp; dead<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly enemy, whom he eſteemed now in worſe ſtate, and more mi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſerable then himſelfe.</p>
            <p>Now to leave the dead man (as no doubt hee is) with the Lord: it is not amiſſe breifely to declare by what meanes the of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fender eſcaped.</p>
            <p>Preſently after hee had committed this cruelty, hee poſted home to his fathers houſe, on the backſide, and the truth of his fact being now knowne, many that were already aſſembled, &amp; knewe not at the firſt about what matter; came to apprehend the fellon. But his father fearing leaſt in that deſperate heate he ſhould doe ſome more miſchiefe, did what hee could to pacifie the tumult vntill the conſtables came, and then delivered him.
<pb facs="tcp:11643:4"/>
They ſending for three or foure of ſuch as they thought beſt, which had ſome of them ſeene the wounds, aſwell as one of the conſtables himſelfe had done, carried him to a Iuſtice. Where either for lacke of their due information of the truth, or by the corrupt, and favourable affection of the magiſtrate, or both, there was a very ſlender baile taken, and the malefactor by this ſleight ſent away.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="to_the_reader">
            <head>To the Reader.</head>
            <p>FOr that ſome of <hi>Cartwrights</hi> favourites wanting colour to excuſe altogither the fowleneſſe of his fact, doe yet inde<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vour to qualifie the ſame in what meaſure they can, affir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ming that he being a young man, was provoked, and ſtirred vp by evill words to commit that in the heat of his bloud which o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwaies he would neuer haue committed: And ſome others beeing themſelues either of a looſe converſation, or at the leaſt enemies to the Miniſterie of the Goſpel, would ſeeme to exte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nuate the crime, by imputing it, as a iuſt reward due, not only to the party murthered, but alſo to the moſt of his calling for their over-bold checking, and (as they tearme it) domineering over their betters, becauſe indeede, they reproue the generall cor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ruptions that ſo abound in every corner: And leaſt alſo it might happily be ſurmiſed by ſome indifferently affected, that many things in this relation might partially proceede in favour of the dead man from ſome of his friendes, it is therefore thought fit for the better ſatiſfying of the later ſorte, to aſſure them that there is nothing ſet downe, but that which is to bee iuſtified by very ſufficient proofe: and for the better anſwering of the for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mer ſcandalls, and ſuch like, here be annexed the teſtimony (as it were) of fowre ſubſtantiall Iuries, which ſpeake of their credit what they knew concerning the man. The firſt doth conſiſt of the better ſort of his pariſhioners where hee remained: the ſe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cond of the chiefe of ſuch Miniſters among whom he conver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſed: the thirde of the worſhipfull in the countrey to whom hee was beſt knowne: and the fourth, of the learned in the Vni<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verſitie where he was brought vp.</p>
         </div>
         <div type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:11643:5"/>
            <head>The teſtimony of his Pariſhioners.</head>
            <p>FOraſmuch as ſome vncharitable people not ſatiſfied with the guiltleſſe bloud of <hi>M. Storre</hi> our late Miniſter, giue out ſlanderous ſpeeches againſt him now dead, as pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceeding from vs his pariſhioners: we therefore willing to cleare our ſelues from ſuch vntruthes doe giue to vnderſtand to who<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> theſe preſents ſhall come, that as (no doubt) the fact was hay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nous before God, ſo is it a thing moſt grievous vnto vs, aſwell in regard of his wife, and fiue ſmall children, whoſe ſtaffe of bread (as himſelfe ſaid) by this meanes is broken, as alſo chiefly that ſuch a man ſhoulde thus periſh among vs, whoſe learning dili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gence, and dexteritie in teaching the word of God was equall (as we are perſwaded) to the better ſort of his fellow Miniſters: his converſation ſo anſwerable to his doctrine, and his carriage ſuch in all his affaires, that (in our iudgement) it might haue bin a preſident to direct a civill, and chriſtian life. Thus having wit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neſſed the truth in the premiſſes, we ceaſe.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>From Market Raiſin <date>this 17. of April. 1603.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edmund Wright.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Hum. Chapman.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Da<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="2 letters">
                              <desc>••</desc>
                           </gap>otte.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Rutter.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Rich. Pockley.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Alexan. La<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ming.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Robert Lillie.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Tho. Brakes.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Mich. Ieſoppe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Rich. Wright.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chri. Gyfford.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Will. Wright.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chriſt. Wright.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Mich. Hanſon.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Hen. Parker.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Pet. Parker.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Thom. Harwicke.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>William Dannotte.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Cater.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>William Hanſley.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Leonard Hill.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Tayler.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iames Robinſon.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edw. Fawſitte.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:11643:5"/>
            <head>The teſtimony of Preachers, halfe of them Doctors, &amp; Batchelare of Divinitie, and the reſt Maſters of Art.</head>
            <p>WHereas vpon the late murther of <hi>William Storre</hi> Mr. of Arts and preacher of market Raiſin in the countie of Lincolne, there haue bin ſette abroach certaine reports tending to his diſgrace in favour (as it is thought) of the offender, vvee therefore the Miniſters to whom he was beſt knowne either by nearneſſe of dwelling, or by converſing with him, doe ſignifie to all thoſe to whom this our teſtimony ſhall come, that we al<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>waies held, and reputed the ſaide <hi>VVilliam Storre,</hi> not onely for his learning &amp; ſufficiency in his calling, a man farre paſſing ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny others: but alſo of ſuch honeſt and commendable bearing of himſelfe in his life, and converſation, that his greateſt adver<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaries could never while he lived (as we are verily perſwaded) iuſtly take exception againſt him.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>In witneſſe whereof we haue ſubſcribed our names this preſent <date>Aprill 1603.</date>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Law. Stanton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Greg. Garth.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Alex. Southwicke.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Chadwicke.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Roger Parker.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Rich. Turſwell</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Theo. Tanzey.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Tho. Burton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Mich. Reniger.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>George Eland.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Hen. Nelſon.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>William Maſon.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Downes.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Amos Bedford.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Cuth. Dale.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn White.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>David Hatcliffe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Will. Symonds.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>William Lownd.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Hugh Browne.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Samuell. Allen,</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Paul Balgaie.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Richard Bateman.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Nic. Clarke.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:11643:6"/>
            <head>The teſtimony of Knightes and Eſquires,</head>
            <p>BEing requeſted for ſome ſpeciall cauſes to deliver vnder our hands what we knew concerning Mr. Storre late Vicar of market Raiſin, we whoſe names ar ſubſcribed, neighbors ſomewhat neare adioyning, thought it our Chriſtian duetie to yeeld teſtimony therein accordingly. And therefore doe ſignify that as we accompt the manner of his death a part of moſt bar<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>barouſe crueltie, ſo we much lament that it happened to a man ſo well approved generally for a good ſcholler, a painfull prea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cher, and for many other commendable partes, which (if by vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>timely death he had not bin cutte of) might otherwaies haue bin greatly beneficiall both to the church, and common wealth.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Gi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ven at Lincolne <date>the 29. of Aprill 1603.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>
                        <hi>George S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> poll.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edward Ayſcoghe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edward Tyrwhitt.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Char. Metham.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Ric. Roſſetter.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Fran. Bullingham</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Phillip Tyrwhitt.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Thomas Grantham.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Thomas Daliſon.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Vincent Ful<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="3 letters">
                              <desc>•••</desc>
                           </gap>by</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Richard Ged<gap reason="illegible" resp="#UOM" extent="1 letter">
                              <desc>•</desc>
                           </gap>ey.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edward Saltmarſh.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
         </div>
         <div type="testimony">
            <pb facs="tcp:11643:6"/>
            <head>The teſtimonie of Doctors, and Bachelors of Divinitie in the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſitie.</head>
            <p>FOraſmuch as wee are intreated by certaine miniſters of the countie of Lincolne to ſignifie what opinio<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> we held of Wil<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liam Storre Mr of Arts, &amp; late fellowe of Corpus Chriſti Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledge, we whoſe names are vnder-written doe by theſe preſents giue him this teſtimonie; that for the time of his aboade in our Vniverſitie he ſhewed himſelfe very ſober, and honeſt in his converſation: he was of quiet cariage in his place, ſtudiouſe, lear<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned, and religiouſe: of great, &amp; ſpeciall hope to prove a worthy member in the Church of Chriſt.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Oxon. <date>Iune. 29. 1603.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>Iohn Howſon Vicecan. Oxon.</item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edmond Lillie.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Richard Kylby.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Raph Kettell.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Aeglionbee.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Nicholas Higges.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Thomas Luddington</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chri. Membry.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Chri. Chalfount.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Robert Burhill.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Rainolds.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Perin.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Williams.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Leon. Hutton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Rich. Crakanthorpe.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Sebeſtian Benfeld,</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Peter Hooker.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Iohn Barcham.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Thomas Holland.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>George Abbott.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Henry Asray.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>William Thorne.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Edward Hyrſt.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Thomas Burton.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Henry Hindle.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>
                        <hi>Richard Alleyne.</hi>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
